<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-02-13T19:35:20-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blog.azuremonk.com</title><subtitle>this blog is aimed at super simplifying and providing clariy for  azure (microsoft cloud) using the written language.</subtitle><author><name>Anand Kumar R</name></author><entry><title type="html">TMUX Simplified in WSL for Visual Studio Code</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/opensource/tmux-in-vscode-for-windows-guys/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TMUX Simplified in WSL for Visual Studio Code" /><published>2020-02-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-12T16:28:02-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/opensource/tmux-in-vscode-for-windows-guys</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/opensource/tmux-in-vscode-for-windows-guys/">&lt;p&gt;Hello How is this&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Anand Kumar R</name></author><category term="kubernetes" /><category term="tmux" /><category term="visualstudiocode" /><summary type="html">TMUX simplified for Windows guys</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How goals failed me - and what worked in 2019</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/productivity/how-goals-failed-me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How goals failed me - and what worked in 2019" /><published>2020-01-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-04T16:20:02-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/productivity/how-goals-failed-me</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/productivity/how-goals-failed-me/">&lt;p class=&quot;notice--success&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Voice in my head: Why on earth would someone want to listen to my systems or routine ???! You must be crazy. 
 I acknowledge but still ignore the voice and continue writing, Why ?? You have these folks to blame - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DEOvAu0knsU&quot;&gt;Dona Sarkar&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xcmI5SSQLmE&quot;&gt;Obvious to you, amazing to others&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Show-Your-Work-Austin-Kleon/dp/076117897X&quot;&gt;Show Your Work&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have always been a very ambitious goal setter all my life, but have been a terrible failure when it comes to execution - it would never last more than a few days. Something changed in 2019, I re-/read these amazing books -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Deep-Work-Focused-Success-Distracted/dp/1455586692&quot;&gt;Deep Work - Cal Newport&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/How-Fail-Almost-Everything-Still-ebook/dp/B00COOFBA4&quot;&gt;How to fail at almost everything and still win big - Scott Adams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Atomic-Habits-Proven-Build-Break/dp/0735211299&quot;&gt;Atomic habits - James Clear&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t read these books - stop reading this post and go read those books - will be a better use of your time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extracting the essence from these three books, I am now a strong believer of incremental tiny boring progress and building a system rather than an ambitious fancy goal. This has helped me have the longest streak to sticking to these routines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mindfulness-meditation&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Mindfulness Meditation&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to delve into the benefits of mindfulness, there are a gazillion articles out there. For me this is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://mayooshin.com/keystone-habits/&quot;&gt;keystone&lt;/a&gt; habit - and the most important one&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;what-do-i-do&quot;&gt;What do I do&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I practice this method. In plain English here’s what I do - focus and observe your breath and body sensations - in a nonjudgmental and equanimous way - THAT’S IT - it’s as simple as that - I SWEAR. I try to aim for 20 mins/day but I’m not too ambitious even if I can get done 1 minute - I consider that a win for the day ( &lt;a href=&quot;https://jamesclear.com/goals-systems&quot;&gt;Systems v/s goals&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;how-has-it-helped-me&quot;&gt;How has it helped me&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Focus, Clarity and creativity - it’s amazing how these foundational skills affect every single aspect of your life&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;screen-time&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Screen time&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Screen addiction is real. If I was bored or when I was in the train with nothing to do - I used to stare at my phone screen. I had to change this, because I have had a taste of how useful boredom can be for creativity in the past - but never managed to stick to the discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;what-did-i-do&quot;&gt;What did I do&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I followed Cal Newport’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Digital-Minimalism-Choosing-Focused-Noisy/dp/0525536515&quot;&gt;advice&lt;/a&gt; - uninstalled all the apps which was distracting the most (for me it was - WhatsApp, Facebook) for 30 days.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;how-has-it-helped-me-1&quot;&gt;How has it helped me&lt;/h3&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;It helped me feel &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2017/01/clive-thompson-7/&quot;&gt;“boredom”&lt;/a&gt; again !! I know this sounds crazy - but trust me boredom is super essential. And now I have reinstalled the apps and use a screen time limit of 6mins/day - so it’s more intentional when I use these apps.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;one-new-thing-a-day&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;One new thing a day&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to mindlessly consume lots of content and not really absorbing it or internalizing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;what-did-i-do-1&quot;&gt;What did I do&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Starting late 2019, I have a tiny book where I make 1 or 2 sentence notes of what I learned that day (kept it small and atomic) - it could be from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://azuremonk.com/audio/&quot;&gt;podcast guest&lt;/a&gt;, my customers and colleagues who I work with, an article/book/video I watched, my 1.5 year daughter, my wife, the cashier at Walmart -ANYONE.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;how-has-it-helped-me-2&quot;&gt;How has it helped me&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I feel terrible when I miss a day of note taking, so all day this subconsciously helps put me in a mindset where I make it a point to learn at least one thing. I personally feel having this mindset has helped me learn and absorb so much from the amazing people around me and has provided me with new opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-aim-to-add-in-2020&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;What I aim to add in 2020&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;physical-exercise&quot;&gt;Physical exercise&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I’m aiming for 10 minutes/day of really slow jogging and gradually add on if and when I feel comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;morning-pages&quot;&gt;Morning pages&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2014/oct/03/morning-pages-change-your-life-oliver-burkeman&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is how to do it -750 free flowing words as soon as you wake up. The few days I have written morning pages in the past - I have had really crazy unique ideas and I had no idea how they came to me, which have totally caught me by surprise. But again this requires a certain discipline and I’m hoping to build this muscle this year.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;www.azuremonk.com&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Anand Kumar R</name></author><category term="atomichabits" /><category term="mindfulness" /><summary type="html">My reflection on what failed and what worked</summary></entry></feed>